Guide to The Glines Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
The Glines records
1975-2010
MS 1920
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
25.0
(33 boxes)
The collection consists of general files, correspondence, publicity materials, scripts, photographs, audiotapes, memorabilia, and financial files relating to The Glines. The records document the administrative and creative functions of the organization and its role in supporting gay arts and artists and AIDS awareness.
Glines
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of The Glines, 2008-2016.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Associated Materials
John Glines Papers (MS 1895). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Biographical / Historical
The Glines was founded in 1976 by John Glines, Barry Laine and Jerry Tobin in New York City. The Glines mission is the production and promotion of gay art, including theater, the visual arts, and poetry. The Glines has won numerous creative and community awards. One of its most notable successes was the production of Harvey Fierstein's Torch Song Trilogy, which won Tony awards for Best Play and Best Actor. Other notable projects include Stamp Out AIDS (1985), a precursor to Broadway Cares: Equity Fights AIDS, and the Gay American Arts Festival.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of topical files, correspondence, publicity materials, scripts, photographs, audiotapes, memorabilia, and financial files relating to The Glines. The records document the administrative and creative functions of the theater and its role in supporting gay arts and artists and AIDS awareness. The bulk of the records document productions and projects.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Gay theater -- United States; Gays and the performing arts; Off-Broadway theater; LGBTQ resource; Glines, John; Glines
- Records
  - Topical files
    - Awards, 1979-2000 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Glines, John
      - "The Glines, a forum for the gay experience..." by John Glines, Circa 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - News clippings, 1983-1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - Oversize, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Photographs, Circa 1990s-2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - Oversize, Undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Groups and actors, general
      - Cast and affiliate biographical sketches, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Head shots, Circa 1970s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Gay Theater Alliance, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - New York Gay Community Marching Band, 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
      - Radical Lesbian Feminist Terrorist Comedy Group, photographs, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Split Britches Theater Company, Circa 1981 (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
    - Reviews, Circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Productions
    Scope and Contents
    The summaries list events and their descriptions by year. Production files, arranged alphabetically, contain publicity material, news clippings, and photographs unless otherwise noted.
    - Production schedule summaries, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - After Eleven, script, Undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - All American Movin' Muscle, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 14-15)
    - Always a Bridesmaid, Never a Groom, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
    - Anniversary celebrations, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Posters, 1982-1986 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Arrivederci Papa
      - Script, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Poster, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - As Is
      - News clippings and photograph, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Playbills and reviews, 1984-1987 (Box 13, Folder 20-22)
      - Reviews, 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
      - Photographs, 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Blue Fish Cove
      - "2 montages: Reaction to Last Summer at Blue Fish Cove", 1981 June 18; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
      - Sound tape, Circa 1981; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 6)
    - Body and Soul
      - Correspondence, reviews, photographs, advertisements, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Photographs, reviews, script, advertisement, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 5-7)
      - Poster, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Both Sides of the Closet Door, review, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Boy on a Lonely Journey, advertisement, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Broadway Cares, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Brothers, photograph, Undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Butterflies and Tigers, poster, Undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Carla's Song
      - Advertisement, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Advertisements, reviews, script, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Sound tape, Undated; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 7)
      - Sound tape backup, Undated; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 8)
    - Chicken Delight
      - Advertisements, correspondence, reviews, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Poster, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - The Classic Question, script, Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Dancing on Ice, poster, Undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Dirty Blonde, poster, Undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Dream Man, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
    - A Drop in the Pudding, photographs, Undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Earl, Ollie, Austin, and Ralph
      - Poster, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Reviews, photographs, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
    - Evening With Quentin Crisp
      - Programs, photographs, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
      - Poster, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Fascination, photographs, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Forever After
      - Photographs, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Poster, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Forget Him, script, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Fundraiser, poster, Undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Gay American Arts Festival
      - Advertisements, programs, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Poster, 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Gay Arts Festival Week, 1980-1984, undated (Box 15, Folder 16-18)
    - Get Used to It, photographs, Undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Gerty Gerty Gerty Stein is Back Back Back, photographs, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Ginsberg and Orlovsky, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - God Bless Coney
      - Poster, 1978 (Box 26)
      - Sound tape, Circa 1978; 3 audiotapes (Reel-to-reel) (Box 9–11)
    - Gulp!
      - Photographs, advertisement, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 22-23)
      - Poster, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Heavenly Days, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 24-25)
    - Hero of My Own Life, photographs, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - High String Quartet, poster, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - How Many Tomorrows, Circa 1980s (Box 15, Folder 27-28)
    - How Now, Voyager, photographs, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - If This Isn't Love
      - Programs, photographs, Circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
      - Poster, Circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Key West
      - Photographs, advertisement, Undated (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
      - Poster, Undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Last Chance at the Brass Ring
      - Script, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Photographs, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Last Summer at Bluefish Cove, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
    - Loren, script, Undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - A Loss of Memory, script, Undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Lovers, script, Undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Melody of the Glittering Parrot, script, Undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Men, photographs, Undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Men of Manhattan
      - Photographs, advertisements, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
      - Poster, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Men Together, photographs, Circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Miss Gulch Returns, advertisement, Undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Murder at Rutherford House
      - Advertisements, Circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Script, Circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Murder in Disguise
      - Advertisements, photographs, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
      - Masks, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Poster, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - My Blue Heaven
      - Photographs, reviews, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
      - Poster, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Sound tape, (reel-to-reel), Undated (Box 12)
    - News Boy
      - Advertisements, Reviews, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Photographs, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Playbill, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Poster, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Nooses, Knives, and Lovers, poster, Undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - On Tina Tuna Walk
      - Advertisements, photographs, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
      - Poster, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - A Perfect Relationship, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
    - Pines '79, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
    - The Quintessential Image
      - Flyer, photographs, Undated (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
      - Poster, Undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Richmond Jim, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Photograph, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - The Rights
      - Photographs, Undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Poster, Undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Round 2, review, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Say de Kooning, script, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Snow Orchid
      - Programs, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Poster, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Soft Core Kid
      - Flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Reviews, photographs, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
    - Sordid Lives, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Soul Survivor, script, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Stage Struck, script, Undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Stamp Out AIDS
      - Clippings, correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Contacts, schedules, advertisements, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence, advertisements, clippings, photographs, 1986-1990 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
      - Posters, 1984-1987 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Summer at the Spruce, photographs, 1979,1987 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - T-Shirts
      - Photographs, reviews, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
      - Poster, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Thor's Day, 1997, undated (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - Torch Song Trilogy
      - Playbills, advertisements, reviews, photographs, 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
      - Poster, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Poster, Undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Touch and Go, photographs, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Untold Decades, reviews and advertisements, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - War Widow, photographs, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - West Street Gang photographs, 1979, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Whoop Dee Doo!
      - Photographs, script, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
      - Poster, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Wild Blue
      - Photographs, reviews, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
      - Poster, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Wind Beneath My Wings, Undated (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
    - Wonderful Lives reviews, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified productions, photographs, 1976-2000s (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
  - Financial records
    - General
      - Accountant Reports, 1996-2004 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Income Taxes, 1990-1998 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Financial Statements, 1980-2000 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Actor's Equity Association, 1993-1994 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Box Office Statements, 1993-1994 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    - Charities Bureau, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Consultant Service Fee, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Contact Sheets, 1987-1998 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Fee Agreements, 1993-1998 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Fundraising, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Helen Hayes Theater Financial, 2001-2004 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Ledger and Business Records, 1994-2003 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Letters of Agreement, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Letters, Ledger, and Business Records, 1994-2003 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Payroll, 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
    - Royalty Statements, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
    - Royalty Statements, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Royalty Waivers, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Statements and vouchers, Circa 1990-2001 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Tax Returns for Postage Stamp Xtravaganzas, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Unemployment, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Workers Compensation, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Performance Finances
      - As Is
        - Financial Statements, Letters, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Whoop Dee Doo!
        - Box Office, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 8)
        - Business Agreements, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 9)
        - Contact Sheets, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
        - Expenses, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 3-5)
        - Payroll, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 6)
        - Production Receipts, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 7-9)
  - Artifacts and memorabilia
    - Award (plaque), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Glines Inc. seal, Undated (Box 27)
    - Stamp Out Aids mug, 1986-1987 (Box 27)
    - Stamp Out Aids seal, 1986 (Box 27)
    - T-shirts, circa 1978-1985 (Box 3–4)
- Additional Material, 1975-2000; Accession 2010-M-070
  The accession consists of primarily of programs, photographs, correspondence, financial records, and news clippings pertaining to The Glines and its productions. Much of the material appears to have been maintained in scrapbooks that were dismantled prior to transfer.
  - Topical files
    - Awards, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Material includes awards programs and clippings.
    - Broadway Cares thank you letters and fundraiser program, 1988, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chambers, Jane and Harvey Fierstein: Human Dignity Award, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gay theater clippings and memo, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Glines
      - Articles, questionnaire, fundraising letters, 1976-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Blank stationary, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Bylaws, Board of Directors meeting minutes, financial forms, 1978-2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Glines, John, 1976-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Material includes articles, fliers, correspondence, programs, and invitations.
    - Groups and actors, general
      - Head shots, Circa 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - TOSOS (The Other Side of Silence), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Productions
    - General, 1976-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11-15)
      General
      Includes material related to multiple productions including some listed individually below.
      - Cast photographs, unidentified productions, Circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Adjoining Trances, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - All American Movin' Muscle, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Arrivederci, Papa, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - As Is
      - Broadway stage manager cue book, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Clippings, reviews, programs, publicity material, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20-23)
      - Photograph of John Glines, Jerry Tobin, and Barry Laine at opening night party at Sardi's, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Playbill and ticket, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Slides, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Carla's Song, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Connections of the Heart, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Dancing on Ice, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Drag Queens on Trial, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - A Drop in the Pudding, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Earl, Ollie, Austin, and Ralph, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - An Evening with Quentin Crisp, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Fascination, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Gay American Arts Festival
      - First, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Second, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Get Used To It, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Good Sense, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Gulp!
      - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Houston, Texas production, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Happy Birthday, Daddy, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Heavenly Days, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Here We Go Again, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Hot Peaches, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - How Many Tomorrows, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - How Now, Voyager, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - If This Isn't Love, 1982, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - In Her Own Words, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - The Jumping Place, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Key West, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Lady-Like, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Landscape with Male Figures, 19901-991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Last Summer at Bluefish Cove, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - The Love Match, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Men of Manhattan
      - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        Includes slides.
      - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Men Together, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - An MGM Christmas, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Miracle on West Broadway, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Murder in Disguise, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - My Blue Heaven, 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - New Play Series, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Newsboy, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Nooses, Knives, and Lovers, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Once Below a Lighthouse, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - On Tina Tuna Walk, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - A Perfect Relationship, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Pines '79, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - The Quintessential Image, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Sex Symbols, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - So Much in Common, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Soft Core Kid, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Soul Survivor, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Special Gifts, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Stamp Out AIDS, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Dallas Gay Pride parade photographs, 1986 September (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Swap, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - T-Shirts, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Thor's Day, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Torch Song Trilogy
      - 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 39-41)
      - 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - Trevor, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Robin Tyler, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Untold Decades, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - War Widow, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Welcome to Chelsea, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Whoop-Dee-Doo!, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Wild Blue, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Wind Beneath My Wings, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Wonderful Lives, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Financial records
    - Box office records for The Glines, 1976-1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - USPS business reply annual permit fee receipt, 1988 March 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Performance finances
      - As Is
        - Partnership agreement, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Key West
        - Advertising, box office records, budget, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Lady-Like
        - Financial agreement with author, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Torch Song Trilogy
        - Correspondence concerning royalties, 1981, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Whoop-Dee-Doo!
        - Budget, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
        - Legal agreements, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Additional material, 1976-2010; Accession 2017-M-026
  This accession mainly contains materials related to different theater and caberet projects produced by the Glines and often with writing by John Glines. Project materials include scripts, sheet music in draft and final form, and sketches of sets. There is also correspondence, press clippings, and an award won by John Glines for his and his organization's service to the arts and the LGBT community.
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Projects
    - General, 1977-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "As-Is", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Gulp!", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - "Lane and Wayne" cabaret act, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lawrence Lane solo cabaret act, Circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - One-act plays project, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Torch Song", 1981-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Passion Fruit Award, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 1)